<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.wiscoradio_k9mte.CWTrainer</id>

  <name>CW Trainer</name>
  <summary>Learn Morse code (CW) the Koch way, with copy practice and a QSO sim</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <developer id="io.github.wiscoradio_k9mte">
    <name>Wisco Radio Labs (K9MTE)</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>CW Trainer by Wisco Radio Labs — learn Morse code (CW) the way hams actually use it, from your first two characters to a full on-air contact. Fully offline. No account, no network, no ads.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Koch-method lessons — every character at full speed from lesson one, with Farnsworth spacing; a new character unlocks at 90% accuracy.</li>
      <li>An eight-rung copy ladder — single characters, two-character groups, random letter groups, common words, a wider vocabulary, ham words, callsigns, and full QSO phrases.</li>
      <li>Sending practice with a built-in iambic paddle and straight-key decoder that shows exactly what your fist sends — including the HH "start over" prosign. Fourteen drill categories climb from common words up through DX callsigns, contest fragments, and split/pileup work. Key on screen, with the keyboard, or with your own paddle or straight key through a USB adapter (VBand-compatible — the [ and ] keys).</li>
      <li>A QSO simulator with six kinds of contact — ragchew, POTA, SOTA, IOTA, working DX, and contest — each with its own roles, plus on-air break-in fills, honest signal reports, and a 5-second "get ready" countdown before the code starts.</li>
      <li>International and DX operating — a bundled DXCC entity dataset drives realistic foreign callsigns, prefixes, and exchanges, with a DX walkthrough in the on-air guide.</li>
      <li>Realistic band conditions — selectable receiver filtering (wide / CW 500 Hz / APF), QSB fading, and AGC.</li>
      <li>Reference guides on CW lingo, on-air procedure, and the history of the code.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Made in the Driftless by Wisco Radio Labs (K9MTE). GPL-3.0 · open source · fully offline.</p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.wiscoradio_k9mte.CWTrainer.desktop</launchable>

  <categories>
    <category>Education</category>
    <category>HamRadio</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>morse</keyword>
    <keyword>cw</keyword>
    <keyword>ham radio</keyword>
    <keyword>koch</keyword>
    <keyword>telegraph</keyword>
    <keyword>qso</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/wiscoradio-k9mte/CW-Trainer</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/wiscoradio-k9mte/CW-Trainer/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/wiscoradio-k9mte/CW-Trainer</url>

  <!-- Screenshots referenced by public raw URLs on the main branch — keep them
       committed so the URLs resolve for any AppStream consumer. -->
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Koch-method character lessons</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiscoradio-k9mte/CW-Trainer/main/build/screenshots/WiscoRadioLabs-Learn.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Work a simulated POTA or SOTA contact</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiscoradio-k9mte/CW-Trainer/main/build/screenshots/WiscoRadioLabs-QSO.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Paddle and straight-key sending with a live decoder</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiscoradio-k9mte/CW-Trainer/main/build/screenshots/WiscoRadioLabs-Key.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Copy practice across an eight-rung ladder</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiscoradio-k9mte/CW-Trainer/main/build/screenshots/WiscoRadioLabs-Copy.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Track your progress across sessions, and tune speed, Farnsworth, sidetone, and band conditions</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiscoradio-k9mte/CW-Trainer/main/build/screenshots/WiscoRadioLabs-Progress-Settings.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <!-- No objectionable content: an empty rating means "suitable for everyone". -->
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="2.4.0" date="2026-07-20" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>International and DX operating, plus fairer sending grades:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Work the world — a bundled DXCC entity dataset brings real foreign prefixes and callsigns into the trainer, with two new QSO activities (Work DX and Contest) and a DX walkthrough in the on-air guide.</li>
          <li>Five new sending drills at the hard end of the ladder: DX callsigns, DX exchanges, contest fragments, split and pileup, and abroad callsigns.</li>
          <li>Two copy rungs from a proper word list — "Common words" is now the top 500 of a frequency-ranked list built from public-domain texts, and a new "Wider vocabulary" rung steps up to ranks 1001–5000.</li>
          <li>Your QSO sending is now graded on the elements you actually convey, in any valid on-air form, rather than on matching one scripted wording.</li>
          <li>Compact option menus and a reworked practice layout that keeps the on-screen key reachable without scrolling — better on small and touch screens.</li>
          <li>The support ("Coffee?") link now points to Buy Me a Coffee.</li>
          <li>An arm64 build is now produced and tested natively on every release. It is not yet published to stable, pending validation on real ARM hardware; ARM users can install it from the .snap asset on the GitHub release page.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.3.0" date="2026-06-28" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Smoother QSO practice:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New optional QSO auto-advance — turn it on and a perfect (100%) over continues to the next step on its own, so a clean exchange flows hands-free without leaving the key.</li>
          <li>A friendly reminder at the end of every contact that real QSOs vary — it's all about building your confidence to get on the air.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.2" date="2026-06-28" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>A small fix:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The support ("Coffee?") link now points to Venmo.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.1" date="2026-06-28" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>QSO sending now auto-grades when you finish your over (it previously didn't fire).</li>
          <li>Smaller fixes and polish.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.0" date="2026-06-27" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Less clicking, more operating:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Your sending grades itself the moment you finish a word — no button to press.</li>
          <li>The copy box auto-focuses when it's your turn to type.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.1.0" date="2026-06-27" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>A richer Progress view:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Color-coded bar charts with a 90% mastery line across Learn, Key, and Copy.</li>
          <li>New QSO tracking — your copy and your sending are scored each contact.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.1" date="2026-06-26" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>A small update:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The splash now sends your own callsign in Morse once you've set it, at your saved speed.</li>
          <li>Character and keying speeds now go up to 40 wpm.</li>
          <li>Steadier settings and progress saving across updates.</li>
          <li>A small "Coffee?" link in the header to support development.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.0" date="2026-06-26" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Version 2.0 — a big step up in feedback and progress tracking:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New Progress tab: cross-session history of your lessons, sending, and copy, with dates and trends.</li>
          <li>Fist feedback on your sending — estimated speed, dit/dah weighting, and element, character, and word spacing.</li>
          <li>Eight keying drill categories, from common words to callsigns.</li>
          <li>QSO roles — activator, hunter, chaser, or call/answer CQ — with varied, realistic CQ calls.</li>
          <li>Iambic Mode B for paddle operators (opt-in).</li>
          <li>A roomier, responsive desktop layout.</li>
          <li>Accessibility, onboarding, and many smaller fixes and polish.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2026-06-20" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Answer Koch-method lessons with the keyboard, not just tap/click.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-06-15" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>First public release.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
